<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<info imgPrefix="http://i.imgur.com/" imgSuffix=".png">
	<logo>4Pe8YfI</logo>
	<slogan>An evil mod for Minecraft</slogan>
	<download for="1.6.4" version="0.2.0b">TODO link</download>
	<workingOn>Porting to Minecraft version 1.7</workingOn>
	
	<description>
		EvilCraft is a mod developed by two guys who wanted to get some experience in Minecraft modding.
 		This mod basically adds various evil things to Minecraft, from everything such as little flying
 		monster that will follow you around and try to poison you, to bottles that allow you to store and
 		control the weather.
 	</description>
 	<additionalInformation>
 		This is our first public release of this mod for Minecraft 1.6.4 and the very first thing
 		we plan on doing is porting it to Minecraft 1.7. We do however plan on fixing any bugs you
 		might encounter and we will keep releasing versions for Minecraft 1.6.4 until the next version
 		for Minecraft 1.7 is complete, so please don't hesitate to post any bugs you might find
 		on our bug tracker. If you have suggestions how we could improve our mod or any additions
 		you might want to see in the future, they can also be posted on our bug tracker.
 		We will also be releasing the source code on github very shortly (we're currently working
 		on some documentation), so if you want to contribute you can find us on
 		https://github.com/rubensworks/EvilCraft . You can also contact kroeser directly on https://twitter.com/rubensworks .
 	</additionalInformation>
 	
 	
 	<featuresRemark>NOTE: YOU CAN DISABLE ALMOST EVERY SINGLE FEATURE SEPARATELY IN THE CONFIGURATION FILE</featuresRemark>
 	
 	<elements>
	<element name="Machines">
		<element name="Blood Chest" img="bFE65ei" recipe="b3kMa0n">
            Ever had to repair that precious enchanted diamond sword, only to find out 
            that your limited supply of diamonds has run out? Then you may find the [u]blood 
            chest[/u] a very handy addition ! 
            Just put in whatever tool you want and the blood chest will gradually repair 
            it at only the expense of some [u]blood[/u]. To fill the blood chest, just insert
            any item containing blood into the very left slot and watch how the internal
            blood buffer fills up. But beware ... this chest might add some nasty effects
            to your repaired item (NOTE: this feature can be disabled in the configuration file).
            [img]UHh37KV[/img]
		</element>
		<element name="Blood Infuser" img="mH2YtNA" recipe="okFwJY4">
		    As its name suggests, the [u]blood infuser[/u] can infuse or fill items with [u]blood[/u].
            Simply put an item containing blood in the left slot to fill up the internal blood buffer and put an item
            in the slot directly to the right of the liquid meter to start infusing or filling items with blood.
            Some items that can be filled with blood are vanilla buckets, [u]blood containers[/u] and the [u]blood extractor[/u].
            The blood infuser is also the only way to gain [u]dark power gems[/u] and [u]undead saplings[/u].
            [img]Wdivmxk[/img]
		</element>
        <element name="Environmental Accumulator" img="J5FLxFO">
            The [u]environmental accumulator[/u] allows you to fill [u]weather containers[/u] with the weather that is currently
            active. You do this by throwing an [u]empty weather container[/u] into the brown beam emitted by the accumulator.
            This will suck up the weather, bottle it into the weather container and change the weather to its complete
            opposite (sunshine becomes rain, rain/lightning becomes sunshine).
            Once used, the beam of the environmental accumulator will become black, which means that it is currently
            in a cooldown state. It will remain in this state for about half a Minecraft day, and you can see that it
            has returned to its originally state because the beam will change back to a brown color.
            (NOTE: the cooldown time can be changed in the configuration file)
            Note that this block can not be crafted or picked up and that these blocks only spawn at the centre of [u]dark temples[/u].
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Fluids">
		<element name="Blood" img="vuVQhag">
			Yeah... its liquid blood...
			To obtain blood you can right click a [u]blood stained block[/u] with a [u]blood extractor[/u].
			This blood can then be used in a [u]blood infuser[/u] and [u]blood chest[/u] and stored in [u]blood
			containers[/u], [u]blood extractors[/u] or regular vanilla buckets.
			You can place blood in the world, just like most liquids, after which it will turn into
			[u]hardened blood[/u] after some time, except when it's raining (see the section about hardened blood
			for more information about this).
		</element>
		<element name="Poison" img="7nAk82E">
			EvilCraft also adds liquid [u]poison[/u], but don't worry you won't find it spawning
			in the world, well ... at least not yet.
			To get some poison, just put a water bucket and any poisoned item in a crafting
			table and you will obtain a bucket of poison.
			Examples of poisoned items are poisoned potatoes and [u]poison sacs[/u].
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="World Generation">
		<element name="Dark Ore" img="Vmh5tj9">
			For now, EvilCraft adds only one new ore to the world generation, called [u]dark ore[/u].
			This ore spawns from Y-levels 6 to 66 (see what we did there) and drops [u]dark
			gems[/u] upon breaking. You will at least need an iron tier pickaxe to mine it
			and fortune does have an effect on the drop rate.
		</element>
		<element name="Silverfish Spawn">
			Silverfish spawn blocks can now spawn in any biome!
		</element>
		<element name="Netherfish Spawn">
			Since we added a new mob called [u]netherfish[/u] to the game, we needed a way to
			spawn them. So beware when breaking netherrack, netherbrick or soul sand in the
			nether, because some rather unexpected mobs might spawn...
		</element>
		<element name="Dark Temple" img="iQm7o6j">
			When exploring, you might come across some weird-looking structures called [u]dark temples[/u].
            You can find them at higher places (above Y-level 90) and they should be easy 
            to spot because of the brown beacon beam that is emitted by the environmental accumulator 
            at the centre of the structure.
            Also note that dark temples are the only places where you can find [u]environmental accumulators[/u].
            [img]ef99MJV[/img]
		</element>
		<element name="Evil Dungeon">
			These are kinda like vanilla spawners, except that all mossy cobblestone is
			replaced by bloody cobblestone and instead of 1 vanilla spawner, you might find
			a little more than one...
			So, if it's more dangerous, then what is the gain you might ask? Well, not only
			the number of spawners is increased, but also the number of chests.
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Blocks">
		<element name="Blood Stained Block" img="RCvAnGQ">
			All living creatures are composed of [u]blood[/u], amongst other things, so every now
			and then a mob might spill its blood on the block it has died upon.
			These blocks are called [u]blood stained blocks[/u] and you can extract blood
			from them by right clicking them with a [u]blood extractor[/u].
		</element>
		<element name="Bloody Cobblestone" img="WaVac6Q">
			These blocks can only be found in evil dungeons and serve the same functionality
			as mossy cobblestone does for vanilla dungeons.
		</element>
		<element name="Dark Block" img="aEHs8tN" recipe="WA2PWqS">
			Acts as a storage block for dark gems.
			They're pretty dark and have connected textures by default, so they
			might be useful for building.
		</element>
		<element name="Excrement Pile" img="BUivWbp">
			The whole digestion cycle in Minecraft has finally been completed !
			Animals will drop excrement piles, which act as bonemeal when placed on the ground.
			The only way to pick up an excrement pile is by cleaning it up with a broom, and you
			better clean up your farm every once in a while because these piles can stack like snow.
			Also look out when you encounter such a pile because it has a chance of poisoning when
			you walk through them (NOTE: for animals and entities this can be changed in the
			configuration file).
		</element>
		<element name="Hardened Blood" img="rXYjG07">
			When you place liquid [u]blood[/u] into the world when no rain is falling on it, 
			it will	change into [u]hardened blood[/u] after a small time.
			These blocks will drop [u]hardened blood shards[/u], when a flint and steel
			is used on them and will turn back into liquid blood when rain falls on them.
			Finally, these blocks have connected textures and might be useful when building,
			just don't forget to put a roof above these blocks, or parts of your house might
			literally wash away when it starts to rain...
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Bomb" recipe="3DkYL7w">
			If you ever wanted to lure mobs or players into a trap which killed them
			with lightning, then the lightning bomb is your new friend !
			Just like tnt, it will lit a fuse when a redstone signal is applied to it, but
			instead of spawning a simple explosion, it will spawn several lightning bolts on
			the exact same place as it was placed.
			[img]61UFx8Y[/img]
			[img]6z91US7[/img]
			[img]pPGCx71[/img]
		</element>
		<element name="Obscured Glass" img="H8vtFYR" recipe="sIG0JAH">
			You can see through it like regular glass, but it doesn't let through any light
			at all. Might be useful for building mob farms with a glass ceiling. Also
			it has a connected texture (I think it's clear by now that we love connected
			textures).
		</element>
		<element name="Undead Tree" img="AyrkMPV">
			Who said only zombies can come back from the dead? Just put a dead bush, found
			in deserts into a [u]blood infuser[/u] and you will get an [u]undead sapling[/u],
			which will grow [u]undead trees[/u]. These trees look just like any other tree,
			except that they have [u]undead wood[/u] for their trunk and branches and that 
			the [u]undead leaves[/u] spawned by this tree drip with blood.
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Items">
		<element name="Blood Containers">
			[u]Blood containers[/u] are storages for all your blood needs!
			They come in three sizes: cell, can and basin, in increasing order
			of size.
			When you shift-right click a blood container, you will activate auto-refill mode,
			which will automatically refill an item you hold in your hand with blood, given
			that item can contain blood. 
			This can prove useful when using the [u]blood pearl of teleportation[/u].
			If you activate multiple blood containers, the rate at which the held item is
			refilled will be proportional to the number of activated containers.
[b]Recipes:[/b]
[img]lNkmioA[/img]
[img]MEsLqmi[/img]
[img]glXvDRG[/img]

		</element>
		<element name="Blood Extractor" recipe="Wo2nvKG">
			Probably one of the first EvilCraft items you will craft, the [u]blood extractor[/u]
			allows you to extract blood from [u]blood stained blocks[/u], which will provide
			your main (and only) source of blood.
			Moreover, if you have a blood extractor in your inventory when you hit mobs, it will
			automatically fill up with blood. The bigger the mob, the more blood it has, so
			the faster the blood extractor will fill up.
		</element>
		<element name="Blood Infusion Core" recipe="luMCzty">
			Surround a [u]dark power gem[/u] with 9 [u]hardened blood shards[/u] and you will get a
			blood infusion core, which is the main item used to craft EvilCraft machines such as
			the [u]blood infuser[/u] and [u]blood chest[/u].
		</element>
		<element name="Blood Pearl of Teleportation" recipe="3CDA3vt">
			The [u]blood pearl of teleportation[/u] gives you the powers of an enderman! 
			Or at least... sort of. This pearl actually has the same functionality as an 
			ender pearl: when thrown it will teleport you to blood the pearl has fallen on,
			except that this pearl will not be used up when thrown, instead it uses up a small
			amount of blood stored inside of it when thrown.
			To refill the pearl you can either infuse it with blood in a [u]blood infuser[/u]
			or activate a [u]blood container[/u], after which it will refill whenever
			you hold the pearl in your hand.
		</element>
		<element name="Broom" img="iyJ8d0c">
			Let's see, what else is evil? Ah yes! Witches! They fly on brooms don't they?
			Well now you can too. Just right click a broom to mount it or shift right click it
			to place it into the world.
			The broom can be controlled by pressing forward whilst looking in the direction you
			want to fly to, so the actual steering is done by moving the mouse.
			Note that at the moment brooms can only be found in dungeon chests, but don't worry
			we've got some great plans for the future which might allow you to craft
			maybe just a little more than this basic broom...
		</element>
		<element name="Dark Gem" recipe="gJdVlaA">
			Dark gems are dropped when mining a [u]dark ore[/u], which is added to the 
			world generation just like any ore and can be crafted into storage blocks, called
			[u]dark blocks[/u].
		</element>
		<element name="Dark Power Gem">
			This item can be crafted by infusing a dark gem with blood using the [u]blood infuser[/u].
			Since the blood infuser also requires a dark power gem to craft, an alternative
			way to craft this item is by throwing a dark gem in a pool of at least 5 liquid
			[u]blood[/u] blocks placed in the world, after which it will suck up these blood
			blocks and drop a dark power gem.
		</element>
		<element name="Dark Stick" recipe="AMPAA3x">
			At the moment this item has no use at all, except that it works in all recipes
			which require vanilla sticks. We do however have some plans to use this item
			in recipes in the future.
		</element>
		<element name="Hardened Blood Shard">
			This item is used in the recipes for several items and can be obtained by using
			a flint and steel on a [u]hardened blood[/u] block.
		</element>
		<element name="Lightning Grenade" img="S2RVgWr" recipe="H9VNjnU">
			Lightning is now completely under you control with the [u]lightning grenade[/u]!
			Simply throw it like an ender pearl and it will spawn lightning on the block it
			hits when it falls on the ground.
			Very useful when you want to burn down forests, create supercharged creepers or
			kill your friends with lightning bolts.
		</element>
		<element name="Poison Sac">
			It looks like and ink sac and it's filled with poison!
			These items can only be obtained by killing a [u]Poisonous Libelle[/u].
			This item acts as poisoned item besides poisoned potatoes and can thus be 
			used in recipes that require poisoned items.
		</element>
		<!-- <element name="Redstone Grenade" img="false" recipe="false">
			Works similar to an ender pearl, except that it emits a redstone signal
			to the side of the block it has fallen on.
			Might be useful to light up tnt from a distance...
		</element> -->
		<element name="Weather Container" img="gc6YNru" recipe="xsNlsee">
			Control the weather with weather containers and the environmental accumulator!
			When a weather container is filled with a specific weather type, you can change
			the weather to the weather stored in the weather container by throwing it on the ground.
			When crafting weather containers, they will initially be empty.
			The only way to fill an empty weather container is by throwing it in the
			beam of an [u]environmental accumulator[/u], after which the current weather
			(one of lightning, rain or sunshine) will be bottled into the weather container.
			Also note that some items such as lightning pearls require specific 
			weather containers in order to be crafted.
		</element>
		<element name="Werewolf Bone">
			An item dropped by [u]werewolfs[/u].
			It might have some fun uses in the near future, but for now it has completely
			no use.
		</element>
		<element name="Werewolf Flesh">
			[u]Werewolf flesh[/u] is a rare drop which can be obtained from [u]werewolfs[/u].
			Don't eat it when it is day, you'll just get a stomach ache, at night however...
			this flesh will start to glow and might provide some rather useful effects when eaten.
		</element>
		<element name="Werewolf Fur">
			Another item dropped by [u]werewolves[/u].
			This item can be used in any recipe as a replacement of leather, but has no real
			other purpose for now, though it might have in the near future.
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Entities">
		<element name="Werewolf" img="iRZPHUd">
			Beware of these beasts, if you're not well-prepared they might just single-hit you
			(literally)!
			You shouldn't be able to encounter these at daytime, but look out at night, 
			especially when there is a [u]werewolf villager[/u] standing near you...
		</element>
		<element name="Werewolf Villager" img="JINHxDi">
			Yes, another kind of villager, willing to trade at day but beware of him
			at night, especially when it is full moon...
			For now this villager adds some specific EvilCraft item trades, but there's
			really nothing you can get exclusively through trading.
		</element>
		<element name="Poisonous Libelle" img="UJaj0XW">
			Although these little creatures look rather innocent at first sight, you will
			quickly discover that quite the opposite is true.
			These nasty little mobs spawn in river biomes and will try to hit whatever entities
			they come across including players, passive mobs and other poisonous libelles.
			Upon hitting an entity, they will be poisoned for a short time and they will continue
			to annoy players by following them for as long as they can...
			Moreover, they are really quick and rather small, but have really low health (about
			one hit should suffice to kill them).
			They drop [u]poisoned sacs[/u], which can be used in various crafting recipes.
		</element>
		<element name="Netherfish" img="XzaPYzu">
			Since silverfish weren't evil enough, we added a variant called [u]netherfish[/u]
			to the game. They're just like silverfish, except you can only find them by breaking
			monster egg blocks in the nether, which are added to the nether world generation.
			Oh yeah, did I also mention they can set you on fire?
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Enchantments">
		<element name="General">
		EvilCraft adds four new enchants to Minecraft, which can all be gotten by doing
		regular ol' enchanting. Although most enchants are rather useful, some might be
		pretty ... evil ... But don't worry: you can disable every single enchant in
		the configuration file.
		</element>
		
		<element name="Breaking (I,II and III)">
		This is a very evil enchant, which does the exact opposite of the
		unbreaking enchant: it has a random chance of increasing the damage an
		item takes when you use it to a value over one.
		(NOTE: again, if you find this an annoying feature, you can simply disable
		it in the configuration file)
		</element>
		
		<element name="Life Stealing (I, II and III)">
		As its name implies, this item allows you to steal life from a mob and add it
		to your own. The more damage you deal with a hit and the higher the level
		of the enchant, the higher the amount of life added to the player.
		</element>
		
		<element name="Poison Tip (I, II, and III)">
		Just as the flame enchant allows you to put mobs on fire, this enchant allows
		you to poison mobs. This enchant can be put on any weapon (including bows) and
		the poison effect caused by the enchant will last longer with an increasing level
		of the poison tip enchant.
		</element>
		
		<element name="Unusing (I)">
		[u]Unusing (I)[/u]
		Have you ever broken your favourite enchanted pickaxe by accident because you didn't
		pay notice to the amount of damage it had taken?
		The unusing enchant tries to solve exactly this problem!
		When an item is enchanted with the unusing enchant, you will not be able to use
		the item when it is about to break and you will only be able to use that item again when 
		it has been (partially) repaired.
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Other">
		<element name="Poison Tip Enchantment" recipe="007pTz1">
			To get a [u]poison tip enchantment book[/u], you can either try to randomly enchant
			a book or you can combine a regular book with a poison bucket in a crafting table.
		</element>
		<element name="Poisonous Potato" recipe="5Rpv8x3">
			Becomes poisonous potatoes don't have much use in vanilla crafting, we've added
			added poisonous potatoes to the list of poisoned items, which allows you
			to craft a [u]poison bucket[/u] when combined with a water bucket.
			Moreover, poisonous potatoes can also be crafted by combining a regular potato
			and a [u]poison bucket[/u].
		</element>
		<element name="Potion of Poison" recipe="z4fMqT0">
			EvilCraft allows you to craft potions of poison without having to do any
			brewing: simply combine a glass bottle with a [u]poison bucket[/u].
		</element>
		<element name="Farts" img="51gkECl">
			Ever noticed that whenever a player shifts it looks like he's farting?
			Well what can I say... EvilCraft adds the option to let loose all those internal
			gases. To use this feature, simply press the fart hotkey (by default mapped on
			P) and whenever you shift a fart should be let loose!
			And in case you were wondering: Yes, it does work on servers, so now you don't
			have to fart alone anymore, you can now also do it with friends... I guess...
	</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Cross-mod compatibilities">
		<element name="General">
			This mod is able to communicate with several other mods.
			NOTE: these mods are [b]NOT required[/b], they will only be used when they are available.
		</element>
	
		<element name="Thermal Expansion">
			This mod is compatible with various Thermal Expansion machines, like for example
			the use of the Fluid Transposer that will work exactly the same as the Blood Infuser
			but it will use 1.5X the amount of Blood instead.
		</element>
		
		<element name="BuildCraft">
			We also provide some facades when BuildCraft is installed.
		</element>
		
		<element name="NEI">
			Obviously all of the recipes are also available in the NEI plugin.
		</element>
	</element>
	<element name="Configuration">
		Almost every feature can be disabled and changed in the config file (config/evilcraft.cfg).
		It is however mandatory that config files at server and client side are identical,
		otherwise you might encounter ID conflicts.
	</element>
	<element name="Download and Install">
Download: TODO (0.2.0b)
This mod will become open source very soon, link will appear here...
	</element>
	</elements>
</info>
