<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<info imgPrefix="http://i.imgur.com/" imgSuffix=".png">
	<logo>4Pe8YfI</logo>
	<slogan>An evil mod for Minecraft</slogan>
    <download for="1.7.10" version="0.8.7">http://bit.ly/1KhHqwo</download>
    <download for="1.7.2" version="0.4.1b">http://bit.ly/UG6J4g</download>
    <download for="1.6.4" version="0.4.1b">http://bit.ly/1lJiaBX</download>
	<workingOn>New features, additional content and bugfixes.</workingOn>

	<description>
        EvilCraft is a magic/technical mod that is based on somewhat evil things.
        One day you've discovered a book with the discoveries of an odd being.
        He discovered an ancient source of evil and uses these powers in various technological advancements to initiate a second age of evilness.
 	</description>
 	<additionalInformation>
        Currently updating to MC 1.8 and working on version 0.9.0 of this mod.

        To stay up-to-date with the development of this mod, you can follow [url=https://twitter.com/kroesermc]@kroesermc[/url] on twitter.
    </additionalInformation>

 	<featuresRemark>NOTE: YOU CAN DISABLE ALMOST EVERY SINGLE FEATURE SEPARATELY IN THE CONFIGURATION FILE</featuresRemark>

 	<additionalInformation>
 		NOTE2: In [b]MC 1.6[/b] there is a [b]Blood conflict[/b] if you use [b]Tinkers' Construct[/b], you can solve it by setting the following line in [b]forge.cfg[/b] to false: "B:forceDuplicateFluidBlockCrash=false".
 	</additionalInformation>

 	<elements>
        <element name="Getting Started">
            To get started with this mod you will need to mine at least one [b]Dark Ore[/b] with an [b]Iron Pickaxe[/b] or higher to obtain a [b]Dark Gem[/b].
            You will also need a regular [b]Book[/b], it will soon contain all the information about this mod.

            [center]
            [header=2]1. Craft a Darkened Apple[/header]
            [img]r6btLhmm[/img]

            [header=2]2. Find a meaningless animal[/header]
            [img]UYcsOP0m[/img]

            [header=2]3. Feed it the Darkened Apple and watch it die[/header]
            [img]z157sTtm[/img]

            [header=2]4. Quickly throw the Book into the resulting anomaly[/header]
            [img]1hxgJIfm[/img]

            [header=2]5. Feast on the knowledge, and animal leftovers[/header]
            [img]kf6txQzm[/img]
            [/center]

            As of version 0.8.0, this mod has ingame documentation in the form of this book. If you are using an older version, please refer to the section "Info Pre-0.8.0".
        </element>
        <element name="Spotlights">
            <element name="General">
                Thanks to these people for their awesome spotlights!
            </element>
            <element name="TheDiamondMinecart">[b]0.2.3b[/b]
                [center][media]http://www.youtube.com/embed/aOnjvMASgjA[/media][/center]
            </element>
            <element name="Lekkel124">[b]0.7.1b[/b] (French)
                [center][media]http://www.youtube.com/embed/wmYtGWMuYG8[/media][/center]
            </element>
            <element name="Dartron">[b]0.2.2b[/b]
                [center][media]http://www.youtube.com/embed/sU3n60Mp_pI[/media][/center]
            </element>
            <element name="LittleLizardGaming">[b]0.4.0b[/b]
                [center][media]https://www.youtube.com/embed/1-Z_KIMcVUE[/media][/center]
            </element>
            <element name="QuinGames">[b]0.3.0b[/b] (Dutch)
                [center][media]http://www.youtube.com/embed/p8IgbtCb-YQ[/media][/center]
            </element>
            <element name="EncryptedTonight">[b]0.2.2b[/b]
                [center][media]http://www.youtube.com/embed/e_GLGPpuYGM[/media][/center]
            </element>
        </element>
        <element name="Configuration">
            Almost every feature can be disabled and changed in the config file (config/evilcraft.cfg).
            It is however mandatory that config files at server and client side are identical,
            otherwise you might encounter ID and feature conflicts.


            If you want EvilCraft to work with Blood variants from other mods (like Tinkers' Construct and Blood Magic),
            you can enable all of these in the configuration file.


            When you want to use this mod in an existing world, you can make use of the retrogen feature of EvilCraft.
            To enable it, just start up the mod once until you are on the start screen of Minecraft so that the config file is fully generated.
            After that you can open the config file, and under the 'general' category you should enable 'general.retrogen' by setting it's value to 'true'.
            Even though this will not replace any non-world generated blocks, it is still advises to backup your world before using this feature.


            As of version 0.6.0, EvilCraft provides an extensive way for players and modpack creators to define their own recipes for both regular crafting and machine recipes.
            More information about this can be found on the wiki: https://github.com/CyclopsMC/EvilCraft/wiki/Recipe-XML
        </element>
        <element name="Modpacks">
            Regarding modpacks, anyone is more than welcome to use this mod in any modpack, both public and private.
            There is no need to notify or ask us to use this in your pack, it is always nice to hear when someone decides to use this in their pack tough ;)
        </element>
        <element name="Download and Install">
            [mod="1.7.10"]evilcraft[/mod]
            [mod="1.7.2"]evilcraft[/mod]
            [mod="1.6.4"]evilcraft[/mod]
            Source code: https://github.com/CyclopsMC/EvilCraft
        </element>
        <element name="Info Pre-0.8.0">
            <element name="Machines">
                <element name="Promises">
                    Promises are items that allow you to upgrade your machines.
                    These can be inserted into the [u]Blood Infuser[/u], [u]Spirit Furnace[/u] and [u]Spirit Reanimator[/u].

                    First, you will have to craft a [u]Bowl of Empty Promises[/u]:
                    [img]1NQOZqv[/img]

                    You can fill the bowl by placing it inside a crafting grid together with two [u]Crushed Dark Gem[/u].
                    This [u]Filled Bowl of Empty Promises[/u] must then be infused with blood inside a [u]Blood Infuser[/u].
                    The current [b]tier[/b] of the [u]Blood Infuser[/u] will determine the Strength of the output [u]Bowl of Promises[/u].

                    A [u]Promise of Tenacity[/u] can exist in three tiers, this promise will determine the [b]tier[/b] of the machine.
                    For example, a [u]Blood Infuser[/u] without a [u]Promise of Tenacity[/u] will be at [b]tier 0[/b]. When a [u]Promise of Tenacity III[/u] is inserted, the machine will be of [b]tier 3[/b].

                    Crafting a promise requires three items: [u]Bowl of Promises[/u] of a certain tier, a [u]Promise Acceptor[/u] of a certain mineral and finally a certain reactant item. A [u]Promise Acceptor[/u] is crafted by infusing a mineral block with blood inside the [u]Blood Infuser[/u], for example infusing a [u]Block of Iron[/u] will result in an [u]Iron Promise Acceptor[/u]. The list belows shows all possible promises.

                    [list]
                    [*] [b]Promise of Tenacity I[/b][hr][list]
                        [*] [b]Minimum Bowl of Promises Strength[/b]: Strength 0
                        [*] [b]Promise Acceptor[/b]: Iron Promise Acceptor
                        [*] [b]Reactant[/b]: Spider Eye
                        [*] [b]Effect[/b]: Machine tier 1, tank capacity x2
                        [/list]
                    [*] [b]Promise of Tenacity II[/b][hr][list]
                        [*] [b]Minimum Bowl of Promises Strength[/b]: Strength I
                        [*] [b]Promise Acceptor[/b]: Gold Promise Acceptor
                        [*] [b]Reactant[/b]: Ender Pearl
                        [*] [b]Effect[/b]: Machine tier 2, tank capacity x4
                        [/list]
                    [*] [b]Promise of Tenacity III[/b][hr][list]
                        [*] [b]Minimum Bowl of Promises Strength[/b]: Strength II
                        [*] [b]Promise Acceptor[/b]: Diamond Promise Acceptor
                        [*] [b]Reactant[/b]: Eye of Ender
                        [*] [b]Effect[/b]: Machine tier 3, tank capacity x8
                        [/list]
                    [*] [b]Promise of Velocity[/b][hr][list]
                        [*] [b]Minimum Bowl of Promises Strength[/b]: Strength I
                        [*] [b]Promise Acceptor[/b]: Diamond, Gold or Iron Promise Acceptor
                        [*] [b]Reactant[/b]: Block of Redstone
                        [*] [b]Effect[/b]: Machine speed x2
                        [/list]
                    [*] [b]Promise of Efficiency[/b][hr][list]
                        [*] [b]Minimum Bowl of Promises Strength[/b]: Strength I
                        [*] [b]Promise Acceptor[/b]: Diamond, Gold or Iron Promise Acceptor
                        [*] [b]Reactant[/b]: Lapis Lazuli Block
                        [*] [b]Effect[/b]: Blood usage efficiency x1.5
                        [/list]
                    [/list]
                </element>
                <element name="Blood Chest" img="bFE65ei" recipe="b3kMa0n">
                    Ever had to repair that precious enchanted diamond sword, only to find out
                    that your limited supply of diamonds has run out? Then you may find the [u]blood
                    chest[/u] a very handy addition !
                    Just put in whatever tool you want and the blood chest will gradually repair
                    it at only the expense of some [u]blood[/u]. To fill the blood chest, just insert
                    any item containing blood into the very left slot and watch how the internal
                    blood buffer fills up. But beware ... this chest might add some nasty effects
                    to your repaired item (NOTE: this feature can be disabled in the configuration file).
                    [img]UHh37KV[/img]
                </element>
                <element name="Blood Infuser" img="FUtDwy2" recipe="ymmdqkL">
                    As its name suggests, the [u]blood infuser[/u] can infuse or fill items with [u]blood[/u].
                    Simply put an item containing blood in the left slot to fill up the internal blood buffer and put an item
                    in the slot directly to the right of the liquid meter to start infusing or filling items with blood.
                    Some items that can be filled with blood are vanilla buckets, [u]blood containers[/u] and the [u]blood extractor[/u].
                    The blood infuser is also the only way to gain [u]dark power gems[/u] and [u]undead saplings[/u].
                    [img]Wdivmxk[/img]
                    When NEI is loaded, clicking the arrow inside the GUI will show a list of all items that can be crafted with this machine.
                </element>
                <element name="Box of Eternal Closure" img="9QDMDcJ" recipe="K2ZxZU5">
                    Simply put, this box allows you to capture [u]Vengeance Spirits[/u] using a [u]Vengeance Focus[/u].
                    Once you have filled this box, you can go ahead and use it inside a [u]Spirit Furnace[/u], which will
                    then work as a basic mob drop generator.
                    These boxes can be crafted aswel as found in dungeon chests. Note however, when crafting or finding one,
                    they might already contain something...
                </element>
                <element name="Entangled Chalice" img="HbFBaKZ" recipe="tyVenFI">
                    You will always get two chalices from the crafting recipe. These two chalices are then bound with each other.
                    When a fluid is inserted into one chalice, the content is shared across all bound chalices.
                    If you want to bind another chalice, just replace the middle gold ingot in the crafting recipe with a chalice you wish to bind with.
                </element>
                <element name="Environmental Accumulator" img="J5FLxFO">
                    The [u]environmental accumulator[/u] allows you to fill [u]weather containers[/u] with the weather that is currently
                    active. You do this by throwing an [u]empty weather container[/u] into the brown beam emitted by the accumulator.
                    This will suck up the weather, bottle it into the weather container and change the weather to its complete
                    opposite (sunshine becomes rain, rain/lightning becomes sunshine).
                    Once used, the beam of the environmental accumulator will become black, which means that it is currently
                    in a cooldown state. It will remain in this state for about half a Minecraft day, and you can see that it
                    has returned to its originally state because the beam will change back to a brown color.
                    (NOTE: the cooldown time can be changed in the configuration file)
                    When this block in recharging, you should get away as fast as possible, because the machine
                    will start accumulating energy from the environment. This will degrade a certain area around
                    the Environmental Accumulator and it will also trigger a bunch of possible bad effects.
                    These effects include (but are not limited to) Biome degradation, Knockbacks, Nausea and Terraforming.
                    All of these effects can be disabled from within the config file if they seem too evil for you.
                    Note that this block can not be crafted or picked up and that these blocks only spawn at the centre of [u]dark temples[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Purifier" img="eorzNTj" recipe="BBveFpy">
                    You know that the [u]Blood Chest[/u] could add some bad enchantments to your tools, right?
                    Well, now there is a way to circumvent this uncomfortability.
                    The Purifier runs on [u]blood[/u] that can be inserted with regular buckets, or your favorite
                    fluid pipes. You just right click with your cursed tool, and for each bucket that is inside
                    the Purifier, one level of bad enchantment will go off the tool. Right click with an empty
                    hand to get back your tool.

                    But hold on, that is not all! The Purifier can also be used to remove random enchantments
                    from tools and move them to books. Since regular books are not 'spongy' enough, you will
                    have to infuse a book with blood to make a [u]Blook[/u], you can insert that inside the
                    Purifier together with your tool. From the moment the Purifier is completely filled with
                    [u]blood[/u], the process will begin.
                    [img]I3fcQc4[/img]
                </element>
                <element name="Sanguinary Pedestal" img="H5JZdKX" recipe="7gDDVlK">
                    It appears that mobs keep dropping from the skies forming [u]Blood Stained Blocks[/u].
                    Since it is quite tiring to manually extract this blood from these blocks, you can now
                    build a pedestal that will automatically extract all stained blocks in a 5x5 area and export
                    it to any fluid accepting pipe or block below or next to it.
                    An upgraded version of the pedestal exists that boosts [u]Blood[/u] extraction output by 50%.
                </element>
                <element name="Spirit Furnace" img="UMk389B" recipe="p2g6llQ">
                    EvilCraft's first multi-block structure! The Spirit Furnace works like a basic mob drop generator;
                    As long as you supply it with [u]blood[/u] and put a [u]Box of Eternal Closure[/u] that contains a
                    [u]Vengeance Spirit[/u] in its left inventory slot, it will cook that captured mob over and over and collect
                    the drops in the four inventory slot to the right.
                    In order to build a [u]Spirit Furnace[/u], you simply need to build a rectangle shape of [u]Dark Blood Bricks[/u]
                    that is hollow inside, at least of size 1x1x1 INSIDE (this means 3x3x3 on the OUTSIDE) and has EXACTLY one
                    [u]Spirit Furnace[/u] (more will NOT work) block inside of one of its walls.
                    Note that depending on the size of the spirit you want to cook, you might have to increase the size of this multi-block
                    so the mob actually has to the space to spawn inside of it.
                    [img]iSY49qr[/img]
                </element>
                <element name="Spirit Reanimator" img="4EqdJl9" recipe="TIxxEBP">
                    Spirits contained in a [u]Box of Eternal Closure[/u] seem to be forever lost, or are they?
                    When placing an egg and [u]Box of Eternal Closure[/u] inside this machine, the spirit inside
                    the given box can be revived at the cost of a large amount of [u]Blood[/u].
                    The spirit will return to the state before it's birth, when it was contained in a spawn egg.
                    Note that only mobs who have a spawn egg can be revived in this manner.
                </element>
            </element>
            <element name="Fluids">
                <element name="Blood" img="vuVQhag">
                    Yeah... its liquid blood...
                    To obtain blood you can right click a [u]blood stained block[/u] with a [u]blood extractor[/u].
                    This blood can then be used in a [u]blood infuser[/u] and [u]blood chest[/u] and stored in [u]blood
                    containers[/u], [u]blood extractors[/u] or regular vanilla buckets.
                    You can place blood in the world, just like most liquids, after which it will turn into
                    [u]hardened blood[/u] after some time, except when it's raining (see the section about hardened blood
                    for more information about this).
                </element>
                <element name="Poison" img="7nAk82E">
                    EvilCraft also adds liquid [u]poison[/u], but don't worry you won't find it spawning
                    in the world, well ... at least not yet.
                    To get some poison, just put a water bucket [b]and an empty bucket[/b] and 4 of any poisoned item in a crafting
                    table and you will obtain a bucket of poison.
                    Examples of poisoned items are poisoned potatoes and [u]poison sacs[/u].
                </element>
            </element>
            <element name="World Generation">
                <element name="Dark Ore" img="Vmh5tj9">
                    For now, EvilCraft adds only one new ore to the world generation, called [u]dark ore[/u].
                    This ore spawns from Y-levels 6 to 66 (see what we did there) and drops [u]dark
                    gems[/u] and [u]crushed dark gems[/u] upon breaking. You will at least need an iron tier
                    pickaxe to mine it and fortune does have an effect on the drop rate of the crushed gems.
                </element>
                <element name="Silverfish Spawn">
                    Silverfish spawn blocks can now spawn in any biome!
                </element>
                <element name="Netherfish Spawn">
                    Since we added a new mob called [u]netherfish[/u] to the game, we needed a way to
                    spawn them. So beware when breaking netherrack, netherbrick or soul sand in the
                    nether, because some rather unexpected mobs might spawn...
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Temple" img="iQm7o6j">
                    When exploring, you might come across some weird-looking structures called [u]dark temples[/u].
                    You can find them at higher places (above Y-level 90) and they should be easy
                    to spot because of the brown beacon beam that is emitted by the environmental accumulator
                    at the centre of the structure.
                    Also note that dark temples are the only places where you can find [u]environmental accumulators[/u].
                    [img]ef99MJV[/img]
                </element>
                <element name="Evil Dungeon">
                    These are kinda like vanilla spawners, except that all mossy cobblestone is
                    replaced by bloody cobblestone and instead of 1 vanilla spawner, you might find
                    a little more than one...
                    So, if it's more dangerous, then what is the gain you might ask? Well, not only
                    the number of spawners is increased, but also the number of chests.
                </element>
            </element>
            <element name="Blocks">
                <element name="Blood Stained Block" img="RCvAnGQ">
                    All living creatures are composed of [u]blood[/u], amongst other things, so every now
                    and then a mob might spill its blood on the block it has died upon.
                    These blocks are called [u]blood stained blocks[/u] and you can extract blood
                    from them by [b]shift + right clicking[/b] them with a [u]blood extractor[/u].
                    When in creative mod, these blocks can be created by simply shift-right clicking on any
                    block with a [u]Creative Blood Drop[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Bloody Cobblestone" img="WaVac6Q">
                    These blocks can only be found in evil dungeons and serve the same functionality
                    as mossy cobblestone does for vanilla dungeons.
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Block" recipe="tYTAeuB">
                    Acts as a storage block for dark gems.
                    They're pretty dark and have connected textures by default, so they
                    might be useful for building.
                    Can also be used as beacon bases.
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Brick" recipe="qdjYY7v">
                    Besides looking like a darker version of stone bricks, this
                    block does nothing special on its own.
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Blood Brick" recipe="HMd8Jsl">
                    In order to craft this block, you have to put a [u]Dark Brick[/u] inside a [u]Blood Infuser[/u] or,
                    if you have Thermal Expansion installed, you can also use a Fluid Transposer.
                    These blocks are the building blocks that are used to make [u]Spirit Furnaces[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Tank" img="PzsYnXg" recipe="cdEYuE8">
                    Previously there were the [u]Blood Containers[/u] for [u]Blood[/u] storage, but now there are the [u]Dark Tanks[/u]!

                    This block can story any type of fluid. It exists in both item and block form, it will keep it's internal Fluid contents when broken.
                    When right-clicking in the air with the block in item-mode, it will toggle auto-supply. When in auto-supply mode, it will fill your
                    currently held item (if it accepts [u]Blood[/u]).
                    When right-clicking the block when in the world, you can toggle auto-export to the bottom side if possible.

                    When you still have old [u]Blood Containers[/u] in your world, you can simply place them in a crafting grid to receive
                    an equivalent Dark Tank while keeping their [u]Blood[/u] contents.

                    When first crafted, it can store 16 buckets worth of liquids.
                    It can be expanded by combining tanks in a crafting grid up until 65536 buckets of storage. (This amount can even be further
                    increased by changing your config file.)
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Power Gem Block" recipe="kuxhNBm">
                    Acts as a storage block for dark power gems.
                    They are similar to the [u]Dark Block[/u]
                </element>
                <element name="Eternal Water Block" img="E2QFyYc">
                    Placing a rainfall [u]Weather Container[/u] in the middle of a crafting grid above a [u]Dark Block[/u] and filling in the remaining with glass panes will
                    result in a infinite water source block.
                </element>
                <element name="Excrement Pile" img="BUivWbp">
                    The whole digestion cycle in Minecraft has finally been completed !
                    Animals will drop excrement piles, which act as bonemeal after a while when placed on the ground.
                    The only way to pick up an excrement pile is by cleaning it up with a broom, and you
                    better clean up your farm every once in a while because these piles can stack like snow.
                    Shift + right clicking with an excrement pile will act as bonemeal, but it is three times
                    more effective as regular bonemeal.
                    Also look out when you encounter such a pile because it has a chance of poisoning when
                    you walk through them (NOTE: for animals and entities this can be changed in the
                    configuration file).
                </element>
                <element name="GemStone Torch" recipe="tU5tFjS">
                    This torch will stop [u]Vengeance Spirit[/u] spawning in a 15 block radius.
                </element>
                <element name="Hardened Blood" img="rXYjG07">
                    When you place liquid [u]blood[/u] into the world when no rain is falling on it,
                    it will	change into [u]hardened blood[/u] after a small time.
                    These blocks will drop [u]hardened blood shards[/u], when a flint and steel
                    is used on them and will turn back into liquid blood when rain falls on them.
                    Finally, these blocks have connected textures and might be useful when building,
                    just don't forget to put a roof above these blocks, or parts of your house might
                    literally wash away when it starts to rain...
                    Hardening of blood will not occur when there is a water source block in an area of four blocks.
                </element>
                <element name="Lightning Bomb" recipe="3DkYL7w">
                    If you ever wanted to lure mobs or players into a trap which killed them
                    with lightning, then the lightning bomb is your new friend !
                    Just like tnt, it will lit a fuse when a redstone signal is applied to it, but
                    instead of spawning a simple explosion, it will spawn several lightning bolts on
                    the exact same place as it was placed.
                    [img]61UFx8Y[/img]
                    [img]6z91US7[/img]
                    [img]pPGCx71[/img]
                </element>
                <element name="Obscured Glass" img="H8vtFYR" recipe="sIG0JAH">
                    You can see through it like regular glass, but it doesn't let through any light
                    at all. Might be useful for building mob farms with a glass ceiling. Also
                    it has a connected texture (I think it's clear by now that we love connected
                    textures).
                </element>
                <element name="Spiked Plate" recipe="eW19IfU">
                    There already exist all kinds of pressure plates, but now there are also pressure plates that
                    can only be activated when mobs walk on them. Unfortunately they also damage any mob that
                    is triggering them. Even worse, when places on a [u]Sanguinary Pedestal[/u], they will collect
                    [u]Blood[/u] from the damaged mob and send it to the pedestal below it. Nasty stuff...
                </element>
                <element name="Undead Tree" img="AyrkMPV">
                    Who said only zombies can come back from the dead? Just put a dead bush, found
                    in deserts into a [u]blood infuser[/u] and you will get an [u]undead sapling[/u],
                    which will grow [u]undead trees[/u]. These trees look just like any other tree,
                    except that they have [u]undead wood[/u] for their trunk and branches and that
                    the [u]undead leaves[/u] spawned by this tree drip with blood.
                </element>
            </element>
            <element name="Items">
                <element name="Blood Containers">
                    [b]As of version 0.6.0 these containers are not usable anymore, use Dark Tanks instead.[/b]
                    [u]Blood containers[/u] are storages for all your blood needs!
                    They come in three sizes: cell, can and basin, in increasing order
                    of size.
                    There is also one Creative Blood Container available (creative-mode only) which
                    can be used as infinite source and drain for blood.
                    When you shift-right click a blood container, you will activate auto-refill mode,
                    which will automatically refill an item you hold in your hand with blood, given
                    that item can contain blood.
                    This can prove useful when using the [u]blood pearl of teleportation[/u].
                    If you activate multiple blood containers, the rate at which the held item is
                    refilled will be proportional to the number of activated containers.
        [b]Recipes:[/b]
        [center]
        [img]lNkmioA[/img]
        [img]MEsLqmi[/img]
        [img]glXvDRG[/img]
        [/center]

                </element>
                <element name="Blood Extractor" recipe="I1sR7e3">
                    Probably one of the first EvilCraft items you will craft, the [u]blood extractor[/u]
                    allows you to extract blood from [u]blood stained blocks[/u], which will provide
                    your main (and only) source of blood.
                    Moreover, if you have a blood extractor in your inventory when you hit mobs, it will
                    automatically fill up with blood. The bigger the mob, the more blood it has, so
                    the faster the blood extractor will fill up.
                </element>
                <element name="Blood Infusion Core" recipe="luMCzty">
                    Surround a [u]dark power gem[/u] with 9 [u]hardened blood shards[/u] and you will get a
                    blood infusion core, which is the main item used to craft EvilCraft machines such as
                    the [u]blood infuser[/u] and [u]blood chest[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Blood Orb">
                    A crafting item which is created by infusing an [u]Empty Orb[/u].
                    The [u]Empty Orb[/u] is created in a crafting grid with one iron ingot in the middle surrounded by
                    four glass blocks of any type.
                </element>
                <element name="Blood Pearl of Teleportation" recipe="LGOintg">
                    The [u]blood pearl of teleportation[/u] gives you the powers of an enderman!
                    Or at least... sort of. This pearl actually has the same functionality as an
                    ender pearl: when thrown it will teleport you to blood the pearl has fallen on,
                    except that this pearl will not be used up when thrown, instead it uses up a small
                    amount of blood stored inside of it when thrown.
                    To refill the pearl you can either infuse it with blood in a [u]blood infuser[/u]
                    or activate a blood container, after which it will refill whenever
                    you hold the pearl in your hand.
                </element>
                <element name="Blood Potash" recipe="lJLvE6M">
                    Infusing bonemeal with [u]Blood[/u] will result in an item that doubles the bonemeal efficiency.
                </element>
                <element name="Blood-Waxed Coal" recipe="tgyWKC9">
                    Infusing coal or charcoal with [u]Blood[/u] will result in an item that doubles the burntime.
                </element>
                <element name="Blook">
                    This is just a Book infused with [u]blood[/u] so that it can be used in the [u]Purifier[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Bound Blood Drop">
                    [b]Only available when Blood Magic is installed![/b]
                    An item that is, just like the Blood Magic items, bound to your Soul Network.
                    It allows for some deep interaction between EvilCraft and Blood Magic by allowing
                    you to access your Soul Network as a simple [u]Blood[/u] fluid container that
                    can be used in all EvilCraft machines. It even has auto-supply mode to
                    power all your EvilCraft tools and gadgets.
                    The conversion rate between Life Essence and Blood is equal to the one defined in
                    the config file for all Blood equivalents.
                </element>
                <element name="Broom" img="iyJ8d0c">
                    Let's see, what else is evil? Ah yes! Witches! They fly on brooms don't they?
                    Well now you can too. Just right click a broom to mount it or shift right click it
                    to place it into the world.
                    The broom can be controlled by pressing forward whilst looking in the direction you
                    want to fly to, so the actual steering is done by moving the mouse.
                    Note that at the moment brooms can only be found in dungeon chests, but don't worry
                    we've got some great plans for the future which might allow you to craft
                    maybe just a little more than this basic broom...
                </element>
                <element name="Burning GemStone" recipe="5vQbABS">
                    If you ever have to deal with [u]Vengeance Spirit[/u], you might want to craft this
                    little item. To craft it, simply put a [u]Dark Block[/u] inside a furnace.
                    But what does it actually do? Well, whenever a [u]Vengeance Spirit[/u] attacks you,
                    you tend to take damage. However, if you have this item on your hotbar, that damage
                    will get converted into hunger! Nifty, isn't it?
                    Just remember that you might get hungry very fast when fighting a lot of
                    [u]Vengeance Spirits[/u], so be sure to pack a stack of your favourite food
                    (tasty chicken omnomnom)!
                </element>
                <element name="Corrupted Tear" recipe="nESU986">
                    A crafting item that is created by infusing a [u]Ghast Tear[/u] with [u]Blood[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Crushed Dark Gem">
                    Crushed Dark Gems can be found as a drop from [u]Dark Ores[/u] or they can be made by
                    putting [u]Dark Gems/Ores[/u] inside a Thermal Expansion Pulverizer.
                    You will need these items to craft various [u]Vengeance items[/u], as well as the
                    [u]Box of Eternal Closure[/u]. Next to that it can also be used as fuel inside a furnace,
                    where it can burn for quite a while.
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Gem" recipe="gJdVlaA">
                    Dark gems are dropped when mining a [u]dark ore[/u], which is added to the
                    world generation just like any ore and can be crafted into storage blocks, called
                    [u]dark blocks[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Power Gem">
                    This item can be crafted by infusing a dark gem with blood using the [u]blood infuser[/u].
                    Since the blood infuser also requires a dark power gem to craft, an alternative
                    way to craft this item is by throwing a dark gem in a pool of at least 5 liquid
                    [u]blood[/u] blocks placed in the world, after which it will suck up these blood
                    blocks and drop a dark power gem.
                </element>
                <element name="Dark Stick" recipe="AMPAA3x">
                    At the moment this item has no use at all, except that it works in all recipes
                    which require vanilla sticks. We do however have some plans to use this item
                    in recipes in the future.
                </element>
                <element name="Dull Dust" recipe="clhzUig">
                    Apparently, redstone can be recreated by infusing a very boring pile of dust with [u]Blood[/u].
                    You do need quite a lot of blood though, so don't expect to stop mining redstone any time soon.
                </element>
                <element name="Ender Tear">
                    A rare drop from the [u]Enderman[/u]. It can be infused with blood to get a [u]Ghast Tear[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Eternal Water Bucket" recipe="5drsGsl">
                    Using the powers of rainfall, you can create a bucket that contains an infinite amount of water.
                </element>
                <element name="Exalted Crafter" img="caH2Mea" recipe="JsX3VDw">
                    A portable item crafter!
                    It has an inventory that is linked to your personal Ender Chest.
                    When the crafter is somewhere inside your inventory, you can press the [u]Exalted Crafter[/u]
                    hotkey (By default 'C') to open the first crafter in your inventory. Pressing that hotkey again
                    will clear the crafting grid. Pressing shift+hotkey will balance all items in the crafting grid, easy for crafting chests!
                    When this item is empowered (struck by lightning), it can not despawn or be destroyed.
                    There also exists a wooden variant that has it's own inventory instead of connecting to
                    your Ender Chest.
                    Has optional support for Inventory Tweaks.
                </element>
                <element name="Hardened Blood Shard">
                    This item is used in the recipes for several items and can be obtained by using
                    a flint and steel on a [u]hardened blood[/u] block.
                    You can also silk touch a [u]hardened blood[/u] block and put in a furnace to get a higher amount of shards.
                    It's red, so maybe you could use it as some kind of red dye?
                </element>
                <element name="Humanoid Flesh">
                    [u]Humanoid flesh[/u] will be dropped when players die.
                    They have similar, yet less powerful, abilities as [u]werewolf flesh[/u].
                    Make sure you don't eat your own flesh though, might cause a bad day...
                </element>
                <element name="Inverted Potentia" recipe="LyXJNQ1">
                    The mysterious power of [u]Potentia Spheres[/u] can be inverted to do even
                    crazier things! When it is inverted, you can't do a lot with it, you will have to
                    empower it to access it's real potential. You can do this by infusing it with the
                    power of lightning, this can be done by either throwing it into the [u]Environmental
                    Accumulator[/u] while there is thunder, or by somehow striking it with an actual
                    lightning strike (make sure it doesn't burn!).
                </element>
                <element name="Invigorating Pendant" recipe="IOU6ZSz">
                    The Minecraft world is filled of bad potion effects.
                    With this pendant, you can get rid of those bad effects on yourself at the cost of some
                    [u]Blood[/u] in this item. The worse the bad effect, the more [u]Blood[/u] will be drained.
                    This item can fit into your Baubles inventory.
                </element>
                <element name="Kineticator" recipe="bMWwA6X">
                    This item can move things towards you within a certain area, for example items and
                    experience orbs.
                    This item needs blood to function. It can be enabled by Shift-Right clicking and
                    it's range can be configured by right-clicking with the item.
                    Fun fact: This item will also function when dropped as item in the world, it doesn't even despawn!
                </element>
                <element name="Lightning Grenade" img="S2RVgWr" recipe="H9VNjnU">
                    Lightning is now completely under you control with the [u]lightning grenade[/u]!
                    Simply throw it like an ender pearl and it will spawn lightning on the block it
                    hits when it falls on the ground.
                    Very useful when you want to burn down forests, create supercharged creepers or
                    kill your friends with lightning bolts.
                </element>
                <element name="Mace of Distortion" img="uuAo7Yl" recipe="TB3A5Ck">
                    Why would you kill every mob in the area one by one?
                    With the [u]Mace of Distortion[/u], you can target all the mobs in a certain area
                    all at once. You can increase this area by clicking and holding right-click, from
                    the moment your release, the damage will be done.
                    A nice side-effect of this weapon is the fact that all the entities withing that
                    given radius also get a knockback dependant on the radius of the attack.
                    The damage and knockback distance can be changed by toggling between power-levels,
                    which can be done by Shift-Right clicking with the item.
                    This item runs on [u]Blood[/u], and the larger the area and power-level, the more
                    blood it will drain for each attack.
                    Note that this weapon also has a decent attack damage when just using it as a regular
                    hit weapon, but this does also drain some blood and will become unusable when ran out
                    of blood.
                </element>
                <element name="Necromancer Staff" recipe="McI3fM5">
                    Ever wanted to use those nasty Zombies in your own advantage?
                    Well, no you can! Just aim at a player (or any other entity that is attackable by zombies) and right click.
                    This will drain some blood of your staff, and send a horde of zombies  (3 to 5) after that entity.
                    After a short period of time (or when the target entity dies), these zombies will die again.
                    This item was suggested by [u]PhillipPriddy[/u] on Reddit!
                </element>
                <element name="Poison Sac">
                    It looks like an ink sac and it's filled with poison!
                    These items can only be obtained by killing a [u]Poisonous Libelle[/u].
                    This item acts as poisoned item besides poisoned potatoes and can thus be
                    used in recipes that require poisoned items.
                </element>
                <element name="Potentia Sphere" recipe="dzmhUQu">
                    A pretty expensive item that has the potential to do great things.
                    It can for example be infused with [u]blood[/u]
                    to make Ender Pearls. This can however be disabled in the config since
                    this is a pretty powerful recipe.
                </element>
                <!-- <element name="Redstone Grenade" img="false" recipe="false">
                    Works similar to an ender pearl, except that it emits a redstone signal
                    to the side of the block it has fallen on.
                    Might be useful to light up tnt from a distance...
                </element> -->
                <element name="Repelling Kineticator" recipe="7vbIpJt">
                    Works just the same as the regular [u]Kineticator[\u], with the only difference
                    that it moves items and experience further away, instead of attracting it.
                </element>
                <element name="Sceptre of Thunder" recipe="Ekag3RT">
                    An early game item to spawn a thunder storm. This item has only one use.
                </element>
                <element name="Spike" recipe="g0PQJxM">
                    Just a simple item used in various crafting recipes.
                </element>
                <element name="Vengeance Focus" img="e15RghZ" recipe="ljDRXJS">
                    It's purple, round and has a hole in the middle. Oh yeah, you can also use this nifty item
                    to temporarely paralyse [u]Vengeance Spirits[/u] and force them into a [u]Box of Eternal Closure[/u].
                    To do that simply point the focus at a [u]Vengeance Spirit[/u] while holding right-click. If there is a
                    [u]Box of Eternal Closure[/u] nearby the spirit should be weakened by the beam and after a couple of
                    seconds it should be sucked into the box.
                </element>
                <element name="Vengeance Pickaxe" img="qMkwD6m" recipe="DjyqbYy">
                    Don't let this pickaxe fool you, it has an awesome fortune X (!) enchant, but that
                    doesn't mean you can use without consequences. Without spoiling too much: make sure
                    you're armored up when using this tool, because you might attract quite a horde of
                    certain mobs when mining. If armor doesn't do the job, maybe consider putting a
                    [u]Burning Gemstone[/u] into your inventory, just to be on the safe side...
                </element>
                <element name="Vein Sword" recipe="Na5G9jf">
                    A very simple early-game sword having the same durability as a gold sword.
                    But this sword has by default Looting II installed on it when crafted.
                    It also provides 2x multiplier for obtaining [u]Blood[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Vengeance Ring" img="kndPmzD" recipe="c9rf40j">
                    The vengeance ring allows you to step into the part of the overworld where [u]Vengeance Spirits[/u]
                    live. If you activate this ring, you will get a few boosts and all [u]Vengeance Spirits[/u] around you
                    will become visible. It's also worth mentioning that [u]Vengeance Spirits[/u] don't like unexpected
                    visitors, so don't expect a warm welcome though...
                    Note that if you have Baubles installed, you can also equip this item into the ring slot.
                </element>
                <element name="Weather Container" img="gc6YNru" recipe="xsNlsee">
                    Control the weather with weather containers and the environmental accumulator!
                    When a weather container is filled with a specific weather type, you can change
                    the weather to the weather stored in the weather container by throwing it on the ground.
                    When crafting weather containers, they will initially be empty.
                    The only way to fill an empty weather container is by throwing it in the
                    beam of an [u]environmental accumulator[/u], after which the current weather
                    (one of lightning, rain or sunshine) will be bottled into the weather container.
                    Also note that some items such as lightning pearls require specific
                    weather containers in order to be crafted.
                    It appears there are also some secret recipes to craft certain Weather Container types, please refer to
                    NEI for these recipes.
                </element>
                <element name="Werewolf Bone">
                    An item dropped by [u]werewolves[/u].
                    It might have some fun uses in the near future, but for now it can at least be used
                    to make 15 bonemeal by putting it in a crafting grid.
                </element>
                <element name="Werewolf Flesh">
                    [u]Werewolf flesh[/u] is a rare drop which can be obtained from [u]werewolves[/u].
                    Don't eat it when it is day, you'll just get a stomach ache, at night however...
                    this flesh will start to glow and might provide some rather useful effects when eaten.
                </element>
                <element name="Werewolf Fur">
                    Another item dropped by [u]werewolves[/u].
                    This item has no real other purpose for now, except that it can be converted into
                    5 leather by putting it in a crafting grid.
                </element>
                <element name="Wooden Exalted Crafter" recipe="9frdpul">
                    A portable item crafter!
                    More information at the [u]Exalted Crafter[/u], works just the same, just with an item-specific inventory.
                </element>
            </element>
            <element name="Entities">
                <element name="Werewolf" img="iRZPHUd">
                    Beware of these beasts, if you're not well-prepared they might just single-hit you
                    (literally)!
                    You shouldn't be able to encounter these at daytime, but look out at night,
                    especially when there is a [u]werewolf villager[/u] standing near you...
                </element>
                <element name="Werewolf Villager" img="JINHxDi">
                    Yes, another kind of villager, willing to trade at day but beware of him
                    at night, especially when it is full moon...
                    For now this villager adds some specific EvilCraft item trades, but there's
                    really nothing you can get exclusively through trading.
                    Rumor has it that villager who are struck by lightning might get werewolf-like traits...
                </element>
                <element name="Poisonous Libelle" img="UJaj0XW">
                    Although these little creatures look rather innocent at first sight, you will
                    quickly discover that quite the opposite is true.
                    These nasty little mobs spawn rarely in river biomes and will try to hit whatever entities
                    they come across including players, passive mobs and other poisonous libelles.
                    Upon hitting an entity, they will be poisoned for a short time and they will continue
                    to annoy players by following them for as long as they can...
                    Moreover, they are really quick and rather small, but have really low health (about
                    one hit should suffice to kill them).
                    By default they won't do direct damage (except for the poison damage) to entities,
                    this can however be enabled in the configs if you like a challenge.
                    They drop [u]poisoned sacs[/u], which can be used in various crafting recipes.
                </element>
                <element name="Netherfish" img="XzaPYzu">
                    Since silverfish weren't evil enough, we added a variant called [u]netherfish[/u]
                    to the game. They're just like silverfish, except you can only find them by breaking
                    monster egg blocks in the nether, which are added to the nether world generation.
                    Oh yeah, did I also mention they can set you on fire?
                </element>
                <element name="Vengeance Spirits" img="yKuQfga">
                    Like their name suggsests, these mobs for the very essence of what was once a living entity.
                    When a mob dies, its spirit is released as a [u]Vengeance Spirit[/u] into the world and
                    will keep on roaming the world for a short amount of time before disappearing. There are even
                    some nasty degraded spirits, that are more powerfull than the average spirit. Under normal
                    conditions these spirits should not bother you and you should not even be able to see them.
                    Be carefull when using one of the Vengeance tools such as the [u]Vengeance Ring[/u] or
                    [u]Vengeance Pickaxe[/u], because these spirits will come after you! If you need extra protection
                    against these creatures, consider crafting a [u]Burning Gemstone[/u].
                    So is there any use for them besides annoying you? I'm glad you asked! You can actually capture
                    these mobs inside a [u]Box of Eternal Closure[/u] using a [u]Vengeance Focus[/u]. Once captured,
                    you can put the box inside a [u]Spirit Furnace[/u], which will then function as a basic mob drop
                    generator, giving you those precious mob drops you so desire.
                </element>
            </element>
            <element name="Enchantments">
                <element name="General">
                EvilCraft adds four new enchants to Minecraft, which can all be gotten by doing
                regular ol' enchanting. Although most enchants are rather useful, some might be
                pretty ... evil ... But don't worry: you can disable every single enchant in
                the configuration file.
                </element>

                <element name="Breaking (I,II and III)">
                This is a very evil enchant, which does the exact opposite of the
                unbreaking enchant: it has a random chance of increasing the damage an
                item takes when you use it to a value over one.
                (NOTE: again, if you find this an annoying feature, you can simply disable
                it in the configuration file)
                </element>

                <element name="Life Stealing (I, II and III)">
                As its name implies, this item allows you to steal life from a mob and add it
                to your own. The more damage you deal with a hit and the higher the level
                of the enchant, the higher the amount of life added to the player.
                The amount of life being added can be changed in the config file.
                </element>

                <element name="Poison Tip (I, II, and III)">
                Just as the flame enchant allows you to put mobs on fire, this enchant allows
                you to poison mobs. This enchant can be put on any weapon (including bows) and
                the poison effect caused by the enchant will last longer with an increasing level
                of the poison tip enchant.
                </element>

                <element name="Unusing (I)">
                Have you ever broken your favourite enchanted pickaxe by accident because you didn't
                pay notice to the amount of damage it had taken?
                The unusing enchant tries to solve exactly this problem!
                When an item is enchanted with the unusing enchant, you will not be able to use
                the item when it is about to break and you will only be able to use that item again when
                it has been (partially) repaired.
                </element>
            </element>
            <element name="Other">
                <element name="Poison Tip Enchantment" recipe="007pTz1">
                    To get a [u]poison tip enchantment book[/u], you can either try to randomly enchant
                    a book or you can combine a regular book with a poison bucket in a crafting table.
                </element>
                <element name="Poisonous Potato" recipe="5Rpv8x3">
                    Becomes poisonous potatoes don't have much use in vanilla crafting, we've added
                    added poisonous potatoes to the list of poisoned items, which allows you
                    to craft a [u]poison bucket[/u] when combined with a water bucket.
                    Moreover, poisonous potatoes can also be crafted by combining a regular potato
                    and a [u]poison bucket[/u].
                </element>
                <element name="Potion of Poison" recipe="z4fMqT0">
                    EvilCraft allows you to craft potions of poison without having to do any
                    brewing: simply combine a glass bottle with a [u]poison bucket[/u].
                </element>
                <!--<element name="Farts" img="51gkECl">
                    Ever noticed that whenever a player shifts it looks like he's farting?
                    Well what can I say... EvilCraft adds the option to let loose all those internal
                    gases. To use this feature, simply press the fart hotkey (by default mapped on
                    P) and whenever you shift a fart should be let loose!
                    And in case you were wondering: Yes, it does work on servers, so now you don't
                    have to fart alone anymore, you can now also do it with friends... I guess...
                </element> -->
            </element>
            <element name="Cross-mod compatibilities">
                <element name="General">
                    This mod is able to communicate with several other mods.
                    NOTE: these mods are [b]NOT required[/b], they will only be used when they are available.
                    As of version 0.6.0, all of these mod interactions can be disabled in the config file.
                </element>

                <element name="Baubles">
                    The Vengeance Ring can be placed in a ring slot, and the Invigorating Pendant fits into the amulet slot.
                </element>

                <element name="Blood Magic">
                    The [u]Bound Blood Drop[/u] items is automatically added when Blood Magic is loaded.
                </element>

                <element name="BuildCraft">
                    We also provide some facades when BuildCraft is installed.
                </element>

                <element name="Forestry">
                    Several items can be placed in the Forestry backpacks. Undead logs and leaves can
                    be placed in the squeezer to recieve blood and sometimes even a Hardened Blood Shard.
                    Undead Sapplings also have Multifarm support.
                </element>

                <element name="Forge Multipart">
                    Regular blocks have microblock support.
                </element>

                <element name="NEI">
                    Obviously all of the recipes are also available in the NEI plugin.
                    Blood Infuser and Environmental Accumulator recipes are also visible.
                </element>

                <element name="Thermal Expansion">
                    This mod is compatible with various Thermal Expansion machines, like for example
                    the use of the Fluid Transposer that will work exactly the same as the Blood Infuser
                    but it will use 1.5X the amount of Blood instead.
                </element>

                <element name="Tinkers' Construct">
                    All Tinkers' Construct tools can be repaired in the Blood Chest.
                    This behavior can be disabled in the config file.
                </element>

                <element name="Version Checker">
                    EvilCraft versions will be checked and can be updated through the Version Checker GUI.
                </element>

                <element name="Waila">
                    Machines status and minor block display improvements.
                </element>

            </element>
        </element>
	</elements>
</info>
